Gaurav Soni

Buhairah Cornish, Sharjah UAE 🏫

+971 50 102 3455 📞

gaurav@allcadservices.com <a>

www.linkedin.com/in/gaurav-soni- in 1a916a53/

https://stackoverflow.com/users/8 93217/gaurav-soni



Have worked in multiple domain and at various positions in the IT industry. Domains include software development, business development, software designing and prototyping and sales and marketing. Good knowledge of the world of Web Development using the latest technology such as AngularJS, NodeJS, JS ES6, Docker and CI CD. Since I have worked in startup I have good experience not only in the software industry but also how businesses work.

Skills

- Agile Development using Scrum and Kanban.
- Experience in DevOPS and continuous integration and deployment
- Understand the Business model of a company for accurate software implementation
- Experience in developing architecture of applications from scratch
- Implementation of component based development
- Contribution to the overall design of application for ease of use
- Assessing and implementing new technologies

Experience

2012 - 2013

Android Developer / BuddyDubai, UAE

BuddyDubai was an application to help tourist with the local information about Dubai.

A tablet could be rented which contained Mobile Data and tourist attractions and offers preloaded. This was an personal project.

My role included

- Application designing
- Application development
- Testing

2013 - 2016(MID)

Software Developer / AllCAD, Jaipur, India

AllCAD Jaipur is an Web Application development company dealing in product development and offshore development. I am also the manager in the company. My primary responsibility was in the technical field. I primarily used the following technology for development – AngularJS, CSS3 (Scss/LESS), GIT, Grunt, Webpack, Jenkins for CI CD and AWS for deployment.

My primary time was spent in the front-end product development, my role included

- Software architecture designing (VISIO)
- UI designing of software
- Technology assessment and implementation
- Software prototyping
- Automated testing using Jasmine
- Assisting junior developers
- Component development for the application

2016(MID) - 2017(END)

Software Developer and Sales/AllCAD, Sharjah

AllCAD Dubai is a branch office of AllCAD India. We were taking orders from Dubai and getting in developed in India office. My Primary role was of

- Software development
- Business analyst
- Project delivery in-charge
- Deployment of software

Alongside software development I was also working on running a café business in Dubai. Here I was incharge of managing the HR, Finance, development of systems and procedures and customer complaints.

2017- CURRENT

Sales and Web Development / AllCAD IT Solutions, Dubai

AllCAD IT Solutions Dubai is an extension of the AllCAD India office. AllCAD Dubai offers services of ELV Solutions, Network solutions and Software Solutions. My primary role was as follows

- Sales team management
- Getting partnership for Bitrix Application
- Training and Development for Bitrix Customers
- Building Bitrix Development team from scratch
- Development of internal Task management Solution for my Company in ReactJs

Technology Portfolio

Programming Languages

Core JavaScript (Very Good)

CSS3 / HTML5 (Good)

LESS, Sass (Good)

NodeJS (Average)

Objective-C (Basic)

Framework and Libraries

React Native (Basic , Learning) Angular (Very good) ReactJs (Good)

Tools and Utilities

Bower, Grunt , Gulp, Webpack
Jasmin for testing
Chrome Dev tools
GIT , GITLAB for SCRUM
Photoshop , Illustrator
AWS, Digital Ocean for deployment
Docker
Jenkins for CI CD

DB

MySQL Firebase MongoDB

Education

2012

B.E Computer Science / Birla Institute of Technology, UAE

- Diploma in Computer Engineering
- B.E Computer Science and Engineering

2006

School / Emirates National School, Sharjah, UAE

• CBSE , 10th Standard

Personal

Interests

Love to create and experiment in the field of technology and hardware such as Arduino. I have recently started blogging where I share my knowledge and articles I find interesting (jsBlogger.me), apart from software I also enjoy activities such as weight lifting, hiking, cycling, travelling and video games.